我还以为你不喜欢乱喊"神啊"
I thought you didn't like taking the Lord's name in vain?
你闭嘴啦
Oh, shut up.
好一阵子没"做"了吧
It's been a while, huh?
不能怪我
Don't blame me.
犯心脏病的人是你又不是我
You're the one who had a heart attack.
医生的确有说让我多运动
Mm, the doctor did say I needed to get more exercise.
他的意思是让你多走走吧
I think he meant walks around the block.
没  他对我使了眼色
No, he winked at me,
然后下半身这么扭动了几下...
and did this little rotation with his hips, like...
我们这周末有任何安排吗
Hey, we got any plans this weekend?
我想我们能开始弄个小菜园
I thought maybe we could get started on the vegetable garden,
然后周日要上教堂嘛
and then, of course, church on Sunday.
听起来可有趣了
Yeah, that does sound fun,
但你觉得我带着小乔治
but what if, instead, I was to go up to Bethy Creek
去克罗斯溪怎么样
with Georgie and do some fishing?
这话你打算拖到什么时候才跟我说
How long you been waiting to spring that on me?
当然是要等到我"扭动"完屁股啊
Well, not till I was done rotating my hips.
你坏死了
You're awful.
所以怎么样
So what do you say?
那谢尔顿呢
What about Sheldon?
他怎么样
What about him?
乔治
George.
你不能总不带他啊
You can't always leave him out.
我没有不带他啊
I'm not leaving him out.
你也知道他对钓鱼的态度
You know how he is about fishing.
弄走它  弄走它
Get it away, get it away!
冷静  它就是个小东西而已
Calm down, it's an itty-bitty thing.
不  我才是小东西好吗
No, I'm an itty-bitty thing!
谁说你一定得带他去钓鱼
Who says you have to take him fishing?
找别的事跟他做嘛
Find something else to do with him.
他会喜欢的事
Something he'd like.
那我们能干嘛  整个周末坐在那里沉思吗
What are we gonna do? Spend the weekend sitting around, thinking?
乔治
George.
你得做出努力啊
You have to make an effort.
不跟自己父亲花时间共处的小男孩
Young boys who don't spend time with their daddies
长大后会变成怪胎
grow up to be oddballs.
亲爱的  我不想戳破现实  但这胎已经很怪了
Honey, I hate to tell you, but that ball is already pretty odd.
求求你嘛
Please.
好啦好啦
Okay, fine.
我再去跟他谈谈  想个事情做
I'll talk to him. We'll think of something.
那就好
Good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
笑什么呢
What?
我只是想起来以前带他去露营
I was just remembering when I took him camping.
有蛾子  蛾子
Moth! Moth!
谢尔顿  只是只蝴蝶而已
Sheldon, it's just a butterfly.
这就有比较好吗
How is that any better?
蝴蝶  蝴蝶
Butterfly, butterfly!
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
小兄弟
Hey, pal.
在玩你的火箭吗
Playing with your rockets?
我是在计算弹道系数
I'm trying to calculate ballistic coefficients.
这也很有趣
Well, that's fun, too.
是这样的  我这周末不用工作
Listen, I don't have to work this weekend;
我在想你有没有兴趣一起做点什么
I was wondering if you wanted to do something together.
比如呢
Like what?
你想做什么都行
Whatever you want.
我的空气净化机需要换滤网了
Well, the filter on my air purifier needs to be changed.
一起去一趟百货公司怎么样
How about a trip to Sears?
我想的是那种活动性更强的事情
Yeah, I was thinking along the lines of something a little more active.
比如去年
Like last year,
我们去钓鱼
we went fishing...
妈  爸爸又想叫我去钓鱼
Mom! Dad's trying to make me go fishing!
没  没有  没那回事
No, no, it's okay.
我们没有要去钓鱼
We're not going fishing.
好的  那就好
All right, good.
不过说真的
But seriously,
钓鱼真的有那么糟吗
was fishing really that bad?
妈  爸又在想说服我
Mom! Dad's trying to convince me
钓鱼没那么糟糕
that fishing wasn't that bad!
别这样
Shh. Come on!
忘了我说的跟钓鱼有关的话
Forget I said anything about fishing.
你就想一想
Just think about it,
我们就做你有兴趣的事情
and we'll do whatever you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
这周末有个航天飞机要发射
There is the launching of the space shuttle this weekend.
航天飞机
Space shuttle?
它们不都是在佛罗里达发射的吗
Don't they do those out of Florida?
是啊  在卡纳维拉尔角
Yes. Cape Canaveral.
谢尔顿  去得开车12到15小时呢
Sheldon, that's-that's like a 12, 15 hour drive.
我懂了  没关系
I understand. Never mind.
行  我们去吧
You know what? Let's do it.
会很有意思的
It'll be fun.
三个库珀家男儿的冒险
The three Cooper boys on a little adventure.
不错吧
Sound good?
不错
Sounds good.
我的计划终于要实现了
My plan was coming together.
我只需要登上航天飞机
I just needed to get on the shuttle
我就可以逃离这个可笑的星球了
so I could finally escape this ridiculous planet.
剧透一下  我还在这星球
Spoiler alert, I'm still here.
谢尔顿  小乔治与我
So, Sheldon, me and Georgie
这周末要来一趟公路旅行
are gonna take a little road trip this weekend,
去看航天飞机升空
see the shuttle launch.
看来我没有什么话语权
Looks like I don't get a vote in this.
很好  你很上道
Oh, good, you're catching on.
不知道能不能见到宇航员
I wonder if we'll get to meet an astronaut.
我记得我还是少女那会儿
I remember when I was a teenager,
超迷恋宇航员小约翰·格伦
I had the biggest crush on John Glenn.
我当时愿意把"那个"都给她
I would've given it up for him no problem.
-妈  -给他什么
- Mom. - Given what up?
她的零用钱  吃你的饭
Her allowance. Just eat.
你们要去多久
So how long are you gonna be gone?
我们星期六一大早就出发
Oh, we'll leave first thing Saturday morning,
在汽车旅馆住一晚
stay the night in a motel,
然后周日一大早就看升空
and see the launch bright and early on Sunday.
真不敢相信我们要去看
I can't believe we're going to see
一个货真价实的航天器
an actual working spacecraft.
看看他多开心
Look how happy he is.
你真棒
Good job.
为什么我不能去
How come I don't get to go?
因为你我姥姥三个人要一起玩
'Cause you, me and Meemaw are gonna have our own fun.
我们能去靶场射击吗
Could we shoot guns at the gun range?
你还太小不能去靶场
Mm, you're too young to go to the gun range.
姥姥就带我去过
Meemaw took me.
我们拉勾说好不泄密  你在干嘛
We pinky swore. What are you doing?
忘了
Oh, yeah.
别听我说的
Don't listen to me.
小孩子爱胡言乱语
I don't know what I'm saying.
我知道你喜欢一直开
I know you like to just keep driving,
直接开到目的地  但是你不能不管
and get where you're going, but you can't ignore
-谢尔顿的如厕时间表  -我知道
- his bathroom schedule. - I know.
他早上第一件事就是要上小号
He goes number one first thing in the morning,
下午再一次  傍晚在一次
then again in the afternoon, once more in the late afternoon,
大概4点4点半  看他喝了多少果汁
say 4:00, 4:30, depending on his juice intake,
然后睡前再一小泡
and then, a quick piddle before bedtime.
"一小泡"  懂了
"Piddle." Got it.
但大号就比较复杂了
Now, number two's a little trickier.
玛丽  放轻松  我能照顾好我儿子
Mary? Relax. I can take care of my son.
我知道
I know.
那就好
Good.
我只是想说
I'm just saying,
如果他不开心或紧张
if he's upset or nervous,
他就会大不出来
he can get all clogged up.
我不会让这事发生的
I won't let that happen.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的  接下来来说食物
Okay, let's talk about food.
不需要
No need to.
他喜欢肉至少要煮到74度以上
He likes his meat cooked to at least 165 degrees,
除了鸡肉  鸡肉得82度
except for chicken, which is 180.
盘子里的食物必须分开放
The different foods can't touch each other on the plate.
只吃袋装的番茄酱与芥末酱
Ketchup and mustard must come out of a packet.
瓶装的不吃
No bottles.
那他对意大利面的问题呢
What about his issues with spaghetti?
这是陷阱题
That's a trick question.
他喜欢吃意大利面
He likes spaghetti.
好吧  我想你能搞定
All right, I guess you got this.
小乔治
Georgie.
起床啦
Up and at 'em.
米希  你的弟弟呢
Missy, where's your brother?
谁管他啊
Who cares?
谢尔顿  你在里面吗
Sheldon, you in there?
爸爸
Dad!
抱歉  小乔治
Sorry, Georgie.
怎么了
What's going on?
我找不到谢尔顿
I can't find Sheldon.
你说找不到他是什么意思
What do you mean, you can't find him?
就是说不知道他上哪去了
I mean I don't know where he is.
他肯定在家里哪里吧
Well, he's got to be somewhere.
或许他的时光机终于能用了
Maybe he got that time machine to work.
到底上哪去了
Where the hell...
乔治
George.
看来他已经准备好出发了
I think he's ready to go.
-等等  小乔治  你的行李包呢  -不需要啊
- Wait, Georgie. Where's your bag? - Don't need one.
我的牙刷在这里呢
Got my toothbrush right here.
换洗衣物呢
What about clothes?
换洗的内裤呢
A change of underwear?
带了
Got it.
小乔治  你要出门两天呢
Georgie, you're gonna be gone for two days.
我可以反过来穿啊
I'll turn them inside out.
-我要前座  -不不
- Shotgun! - No, no.
偶尔换你弟弟坐一次前座
Let your brother sit up front for a change.
我其实比较想坐后座
I actually prefer sitting in the back.
比较安全
It's safer.
来嘛  去前座陪你爸爸
Oh, come on, sit up front with your daddy.
他都不够时间跟你相处
He doesn't get to spend enough time with you.
我先喊了要前座
I called shotgun.
乔治
George.
我们掷硬币决定
We'll flip a coin.
好了吧  小乔治  选边
All right? Georgie, call it.
人头
Heads.
是字
Tails.
-可恶  -谢尔顿  你赢了
- Dang it. - Sheldon, you won.
你坐前座
You get to ride up front.
不能三战两胜吗
Can't we do two out of three?
你赢了  上车
You won. Get in the car.
这年头先喊坐前座没意义了吗
What's the point in calling shotgun?
你是个好爸爸
You're a good dad.
等他俩都活过周日再叫我好爸爸吧
If I don't kill one of them before Sunday, I'm a good dad.
玩得愉快
Have fun.
爱你们
Love you guys.
再见啦  小心开车
Bye! Drive safe!
这是个好主意  这真是个好主意
Oh, this was a good idea, this was a good idea,
是个好主意
this was a good idea.
这是个好主意
This was a good idea.
是不是很兴奋啊
Isn't this exciting?
只有我们三个姑娘  家里没有臭男生
It's just us girls, no boys in the house.
感觉家里已经香了一点呢
The place already smells better.
我们要一起做什么呢
So what are we gonna do?
你有没有兴趣
How would you like
去美容院来个全套美容
to go to the beauty salon and get all done up?
我能像女星辛蒂·罗波一样染橙发吗
Can I have orange hair like Cyndi Lauper?
门都没有
I don't think so.
姥姥就有蓝头发的朋友
Meemaw has friends with blue hair.
的确是啊
She's right.
我还没到那一步
I haven't gone there yet,
但过了某个年龄  不染不行啊
but after a certain age, it's mandatory.
你别想给头发染色
Your hair's not changing color.
抱歉啦孩子
Sorry, kiddo.
你妈最无聊了
Your mom is no fun.
不好意思  我很有趣好吗
Excuse me, I'm fun.
那我可以染头发吗
So I can color my hair?
想都别想
Not a chance.
但我可有趣了
But I'm very much fun.
你想自欺就随你吧
Whatever you need to believe.
希特勒元首
Mein Fuhrer.
爸爸
Dad?
什么事
Yeah?
你有兴趣进行一场对话吗
Would you like to have a conversation?
好啊  当然啦
Yeah. Sure. Absolutely.
好的  你想聊什么
All right, what would you like to talk about?
我想想
Um, well, let's see.
你有没有想过长大以后
Uh... have you given much thought to what you want to be
要干哪一行
when you grow up?
想过
I have.
很好
Great.
所以是什么呢
And what would that be?
很可能是科学家
Oh. Most likely a scientist.
除非我留在德州  那可能是当养牛大亨
Unless I stay in Texas, then I'm thinking cattle baron.
养牛大亨吗
Cattle baron?
前提是我不需要碰到牛
Assuming I don't have to touch the cows.
这还用说
Goes without saying.
你从小就想成为橄榄球教练吗
Did you always want to be a football coach?
我一直想打橄榄球
Well, I always wanted to play.
至少在我受伤前都是
At least till I got hurt.
你打得好吗
Were you a good player?
不怎么样
Eh, not really.
我只是比其他孩子块头大
I was just bigger than the other kids.
所以你的大块头弥补了你的平庸
So you compensated for mediocrity by being large.
我想是吧
I guess.
这在牛身上也同样适用
That works for cattle as well.
谢谢你指出这点
Oh, well, thanks for pointing that out.
不客气
You're welcome.
你们最好打开窗户
You might want to open a window.
要死了
Oh, boy.
我的头好热
My head is so hot.
她真有意思
She is such a hoot.
-你还好吧  -没事
- You okay? - Fine.
那好吧  别告诉我了
Okay, don't tell me.
超热
So hot...
我不喜欢你把我塑造成坏人
I don't like you making me out to be the bad guy
就因为我不让我女儿随心所欲
just 'cause I won't let my daughter do whatever she wants.
我以前也给了你很多自由
I gave you a lot of freedom,
你现在不也挺好
you turned out okay.
你才没有给我自由
You didn't give me freedom.
你总是不在家
You were never around.
是吗
Is that so?
我保证  我给莎琳和爱德华做的晚饭
I guarantee I made supper for Charlene and Edward
比你做的还多
more times than you ever did.
基本上是我养大了他们
I basically raised 'em.
你以为我在外面跳舞享乐吗
You think I was out dancing?
我是在外面打两份工
I was out working two jobs so your daddy could
结果你爸经营快照小铺  把所有钱都赔了个精光
lose all our money on that damn chain of Fotomats!
美国连锁小店  提供冲晒照片服务
通常开在郊区超市停车场或商业区
那个小摊子每次来台风就被吹倒
It wasn't Daddy's fault that those little things blew over
又不是爸的错
every time there was a storm.
说真的  我快融化了
Seriously, I'm melting.
死犰狳
Dead armadillo.
我得三分
That's three for me.
这个开车游戏烂透了
This is a terrible driving game.
如果它还在抽搐  能算路毙动物吗
Is it roadkill if it's still twitchin'?
既死又活  就像薛定谔的猫
Huh, both alive and dead, just like Schrodinger's cat.
我都不知道他有养猫
I didn't know he had a cat.
你听说过薛定谔吗
You've heard of Schrodinger?
当然了  就是《查理·布朗》里
Sure. It's the kid from Charlie Brown
其实是叫史洛德  和查理·布朗与露茜同为《花生漫画》里的角色
弹钢琴的那个小孩
who plays the piano.
露茜暗恋他
Lucy's got a crush on him.
薛定谔的猫是项思想实验
Schrodinger's cat is a thought experiment.
一只猫被关在盒子里  接触放射性物质
A cat in a box is exposed to poison,
在盒子打开前  猫的状态是既生又死
and is both alive and dead until it is observed.
那只猫名叫薛定谔吗
So the cat's name is Schrodinger?
不是
No.
那它叫什么
Well, what's its name?
它的名字不重要
Its name doesn't matter.
如果猫死了就重要了
It does if the cat was dead.
不然它的墓碑上要刻什么名字
Otherwise, what are you gonna put on his tombstone?
这猫估计也不会有墓碑
Not likely the cat's getting a tombstone.
要是葬在宠物墓地里就会有的
It would in a pet cemetery.
好吧  猫的名字叫白手套
Fine, the cat's name is Mittens.
因为它有奶白色的小爪子吗
Because he has little white feet?
是啊
Sure.
那在这项思想实验里
So, in this thought experiment,
你认为小奶猫是生是死呢
do you think Mittens is dead or alive?
在打开盒子前  无法确定
There's no way of saying until you open the box.
别卖关子嘛
Oh, come on.
乐观来说  我选择相信它还活着
Optimistically, I would choose to believe he's alive.
好棒
Yes!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
死乌鸦
Oh, dead crow.
这只毫无疑问是死透了
There ain't no doubt about that one.
郊区汽车旅馆
这里的马桶为了我的安全  已经消毒过了
The toilet was sanitized for my protection.
我超爱这地方
I love this place.
爸爸  我们能去爬虫世界玩吗
Dad, can we go to Reptile World?
不行
No.
那里有超大条的蛇  能一口吞掉整只鸡
They a got snake so big it can eat a whole chicken.
这样的话  不行
Oh, well, in that case, no.
-讨厌  -我们睡觉吧
- Aw. - Let's get some sleep.
我们明天得早起  才能赶到卡纳维拉尔角
We got to get up early if we're gonna get to Cape Canaveral
看航天飞机起飞
in time for liftoff.
我太兴奋了  不知道能不能睡着
I'm so excited, I don't know if I can.
小家伙  你得努力试试  好吗
Well, buddy, you're gonna have to try, all right?
你俩一起睡那张床  我睡这张
You two share that bed, I'll take this one.
-不行  -没门
- No. - Nuh-uh.
别这样  小伙子们  我块头最大
Come on, fellas, I'm the biggest.
我自己睡一张床才合理
It makes sense that I get a bed to myself.
-不行  -没门
- No. - Nuh-uh.
那我们掷硬币决定  小乔治选边
We'll flip for it. Georgie, call it.
人头
Heads.
你今天不走运啊
Not your day.
可恶
Dang it.
-那看起来是人头啊  -去刷你的牙
- That looked like heads. - Go brush your teeth.
这样真的有用吗
This really works?
你的头发到明天还会是一样美美的
Your hair will look just as pretty tomorrow.
睡吧  我给你盖被子
Now, come on, let's tuck you in.
我很庆幸我没染橘色头发
I'm glad I don't have orange hair.
我也是  宝贝
Me, too, baby.
我想像麦当娜一样
I want to be more like Madonna.
你想气死我吗
Are you trying to kill me?
如果是  那你快成功了
'Cause if you are, good job.
她为什么只像处女啊
Why is she only like a virgin?
作风前卫的麦当娜当年的知名歌曲《宛如处女/Like a Virgin》
晚安
Good night!
你准备好继续跟我谈了吗
You ready to finish our conversation?
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to finish.
我把自己抚养成人  就像森林泰山一样
I raised myself like a jungle child.
说完了
End of story.
别那么夸张好吗
Oh, stop being so dramatic.
你以为我不难受吗
You think I didn't feel bad
我也想多陪在你们身边啊
not being around more than I wanted to be?
你真难受吗
Did you?
有一点吧
A little bit.
我在逗你呢  我当然难受了
I'm teasing, come on. Of course I did.
不然我干嘛求你和乔治
Why else would I have begged you and George
搬回梅德福
to move back to Medford?
你是为了和外孙们待在一起
So you could be with your grandchildren.
还有你
And you.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
我的孩子里就只有你还肯跟我说话了
You're the only one of my children still talking to me.
真是毫不意外
No surprise there.
再说了  你把自己养得比我养得还好
Besides, you raised yourself better than I ever could.
你真这么想吗
You actually believe that?
不  但要是你相信了就能原谅我了
No, but it would help my cause if you did.
你头发看起来很美
Your hair looks pretty.
够了
Enough.
爸爸
Dad?
Dad.
干什么
What?
乔治一直踢我
Georgie keeps kicking me.
踢回去
Kick him back.
我不想碰到他
I'd rather not touch him.
你想和我一起睡吗
You want to sleep with me?
想  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
好了
Yeah.
位置够吗
Got enough room?
够了
Yes.
你散发出好多热气啊
You throw off a lot of heat.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事  挺舒服的
That's all right. It's kind of nice.
下雨了他们还发射航天飞机吗
Do they launch those shuttles in the rain?
小雨应该没问题
I think a light rain's okay.
糟了
Oh, no.
会雨过天晴的
It'll pass.
先睡觉吧
Just get some sleep.
雨没过天未晴
It didn't pass.
谢尔顿  我也很遗憾
Sheldon, I'm real sorry.
我跟你说个秘密好吗
Can I tell you a secret?
我一直不知道闪电是如何产生的
I never understood how lightning works.
你的高中没教过吗
Didn't they teach you that in high school?
应该有吧
They probably did,
但我那时打橄榄球  头整天撞来撞去
but I got hit in the head a lot playing football.
你能解释给我听吗
Would you explain it to me?
当正负电荷积累得够多
Well, when positive and negative charges grow large enough,
云内就会产生巨大的闪光
a giant spark occurs in the cloud.
听起来挺酷啊  那打雷是怎么回事
Ah, that-that's pretty cool. What causes the thunder?
是粒子被加热到5500摄氏度时产生的冲击波
It's a shock wave from particles heated to 10,000 degrees.
真有趣
Interesting.
你想知道什么才真的有趣吗
You want to know what's really interesting?
亚里士多德认为打雷的响声
Aristotle thought that the sound of thunder
是由两朵云碰撞产生的
was due to a collision between two clouds.
他认为云朵在排出空气
He believed the clouds were expelling air,
类似火堆上的木头发出噼啪声
in the way a log on a fire crackles...
直到很多年后  我才意识到
I didn't realize until years later
我爸爸问我关于闪电和打雷的问题
that my father was only asking questions
只是为了让我振作起来
about lightning and thunder to cheer me up.
其实呢  他经常装傻扮蠢
In fact, he would often pretend to be dumb
就为了哄我开心
just to make me feel better.
看起来下雨了
Looks like rain.
而我哥哥
My brother, on the other hand,
他不用装  是真的蠢
didn't have to pretend.
好了  数到三我们就跑到车那里去
Okay, on the count of three, we run to the car.
-准备好了吗  一  二  -等等
- Ready? One, two... - Wait.
回家路上我想坐副驾
I want shotgun going back.
好吧  你坐副驾  准备冲了
Fine, you get shotgun. Okay, here we go.
-一  二  -我觉得
- One, two... - I still think
还是应该等雨小点再走
we should wait till the rain slows down.
不行  我们得回家
No, we got to get home.
我明天要上班  你们要上学
I got work tomorrow, you guys got school.
你知道我会被淋湿的吧
You do realize I'll get wet?
只是水而已  谢尔顿
It's just water, Sheldon.
好吧  就是确认一下你知道
All right. Just making sure you realize.
好了  要冲了  预备
All right, here we go. Ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
小兄弟  我们不是计划好了吗
Buddy, I thought we had a plan.
是你计划好了
You had a plan.
我从没能亲眼看到航天器升空
I never did get to see a launch in person,
但那是我最快乐的一趟旅程
but that was the best trip I ever had.
很遗憾我没能在他在世的时告诉他
I wish I had told my father while he was alive.